RISM Collections at New York University Conferences Guide to the Records of New Perspectives on Caribbean Studies: Toward the 21st Century and Prospects for Caribbean Basin Integration (Conference held at Hunter College, CUNY, August 28-September 1, 1984) RISM RG 16 (j)
New York University Archives
- Series I. Correspondence, April 1983 - October 1984, undated
  Scope and Contents note
  .5 linear feet (1 box) arranged chronologically. The series consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence generated by RISM and CUNY conference organizers. Papers in this series highlight planning details and initial outreach efforts to potential participants. Items of interest include correspondence and a report concerning visa restrictions that impacted some conference participants (see Folder 4).
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, form letters brochures, article, ephemera, Apr - Jun 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, ephemera, brochure, July - Dec 1983; undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, Jan - Feb 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re: Congressman Bill Green concerning visas, report: "Visa Denials on Ideological Grounds: An Update," invitations, miscellaneous conference material, Mar 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, Kari Polanyi Levitt curriculum vitae, postcards, newsletter, flyer Item: bibliographic sources on the Netherlands Antilles, Apr 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, form letters, Mar - May 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, mailing lists, Karen Fog Olwig curriculum vitae, project proposal, Jun 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, Jun - July 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re: invitations to U.S. Congressmen and Senators, Jun - Aug 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence re: invitations to Foreign Ambassadors, Jun - Aug 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, postcards, Jean-Claude Garcia Zamor curriculum vitae, ephemera, Jul 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, postcards, Jul 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence re: invitations to foreign officials, Jul 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence re: conference information requests, Fausto Ramos, C. G. Clarke, Frederick J. Conway, Norman Dorsen, Edna Acosta-Belen, Joyce M. Sharpe, postcard, ephemera, Aug 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence re: regrets/accepts, Frederico Fahsen, Jose Francisco Sucre-Figarella, Keith Johnson, Elizabeth Henderson, Georges Rioux, Sonia Shura Diaz, Ramesh Deosaran, Donald A. McLeod, John Echteld, Doris Kitson, E. Ethelbert Miller, Paul R. Latortue, Aug 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence re: congratulations/thanks, M. G. Smith, Victor Navasky, Eddie Greene, Geoffrey Fox, Frank E. Manning, Constance Sutton, K.S. Panton, Rita Gialcone de Romero, Lisbeth Bessil-Watson, Abioseh Davidson Nicol, Sep 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence re: Douglas Ferguson, Robin Elliott, Oct 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence re: Gerry Enlaw, Antonio Lauria, Susanne Jonas, John Echteld, Carl Campbell, Israel D. Drori, Mitchell Seligon, Frances Rothstein, Daneil Weiss; AP article "Mixed Reaction to proposed immigration Bill," ephemera, 1984; undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series II. Grant Funding (removed)
  General note
  Materials in Series II. Grant Funding are at the Reed Foundation.
- Series III. Accounting and Financial Records (removed)
  Materials in Series III. Accounting and Financial Records are at the Reed Foundation.
  - Financial documents returned to the Reed Foundation
- Series IV. Publicity, February 1983 - 1985, undated
  1.0 linear feet (2 boxes), arranged chronologically. This series documents the efforts of RISM and CUNY conference organizers to gain support and promote interest in the conference. Included are minutes, conference programs, correspondence, mailing lists, form letters and invitations. Publicity materials include advertisements, press releases and conference announcements. A number of unique conference flyers and conference brochures are also included (see Box 4, folder 1 below, and Series XIV. Oversized Materials, Box 25). Hunter College newsletters provide a unique post-conference report (see Box 5, folders 29 - 32). For additional post-conference coverage, see Series VII. Clippings.
  - Notes, various flyers and brochures: Item: flyer for Beryl McBurnie, Foundation for the Arts, Feb - May 1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Notes, CUNY Assoc. of Caribbean Studies brochure, Jun - Oct 1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Notes, correspondence, CUNY News & Reviews newsletter, ephemera, Nov - Dec 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, mailing lists for the Nicaragua-Honduras delegation, task force committees, and news media, notes, ephemera, Jan - Dec 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Postal reply cards, correspondence, receipts for mailing permit, Mar - Apr 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--advertising, newsletters, advertising rates, published notices, Mar - Apr 1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of planning meeting, Mar - July 1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1984 conference flyers, Caribbean maps [used for flyers], April 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Mailing lists for flyers and posters A - C, [April 1984?] (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mailing lists for flyers and posters D - K, [April 1984?] (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Mailing lists for flyers and posters L - R, [April 1984?] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Mailing lists for flyers and posters S - Z, [April 1984?] (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Mailing lists -- embassy officials, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Mailing lists -- U.S. House of Representatives, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mailing lists -- Afro-American/ Black Studies Departments, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Form letters to CUNY faculty and administrators; CUNY mailing list, miscellaneous mailing lists, notes, ephemera, May 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mailing list of media contacts sent conference notices, correspondence release form, published conference notices, [May 1984] (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Published conference notices [clipping and newsletters], ephemera, May - Jun 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Medgar Evers conference brochure, correspondence, news media lists, draft conference programs, notes, ephemera, May - Jun 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, requests for conference programs and flyers; brochure, mailing list for the Congressional Black Caucus, miscellaneous lists, notes, ephemera, Jun 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Tribute program (partial) and seating list for tribute to Basil Paterson [names and addresses written on front cover], Jun 1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence re: conference brochures, draft brochure, map, sample registration forms, notes, Jul 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Mighty Sparrow, Donna Shalala correspondence, magazine article about Edna Manley, draft bios of Edna Manley, Mighty Sparrow, George Lamming, conference programs, July - Aug 1984, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Angel G. Quintero-Rivera, Alfred M. Sears, David Fields correspondence, mailing lists, notes, July - Aug 1984, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Conference, program drafts, poster, [July - Aug 1984] (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Conference, program drafts, [July - Aug 1984] (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, published conference notices, journal rates, conference programs, July - Aug 1984, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Conference press release, Aug 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Reception invitations, correspondence, lists of invited participants and observers, ephemera, Aug 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Post-conference correspondence, Sep 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - At Hunter, CUNY Newsletter [Features report on Conference], Oct 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - At Hunter, CUNY Newsletter, Oct 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - At Hunter, CUNY Newsletter, Oct 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - At Hunter, CUNY Newsletter, Oct 1984 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Chancellor's Budget Request, 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The City University of New York Success Book, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Notes, ephemera, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Series V. Conference Registration Papers, February - September 1984
  Scope and Contents note:
  .5 linear feet (1 box), arranged chronologically. The correspondence in this series details arrangements for travel and hotel lodgings, various services as well as the registration process. The papers include conference programs, registration forms, flight schedules and hotel reservations.
  - Correspondence, form letters, hotel reservation lists, brochures, notes, Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pre-registration lists, correspondence, ephemera, [Jun - Aug 1984] (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Pre-registration forms, ephemera, Jun - Aug 1984, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pre-registration forms, Jun - Aug 1984, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, travel schedules for participants, ephemera, Jul - Oct, 1984, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Participant list, conference programs, [Aug - Sept. 1984] (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Registration forms for the general public participants, and media -- A - B, Aug - Sept 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Registration forms for the general public, participants, and media -- C - D, Aug - Sept 1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Registration forms for the general public, participants, and media -- E - H, Aug - Sept 1984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Registration forms for the general public, participants, and media -- I - L, Aug - Sept 1984 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Registration forms for the general public, participants, and media -- M - P, Aug - Sept 1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Registration forms for the general public, participants, and media -- R - S, Aug - Sept 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Registration forms for the general public, participants, and media -- T - Z, Aug - Sept 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence re: food services, music; list of participants to receive mementos, Aug - Sept 1984; undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Series VI. Conference Participants, November 1982 - November 1986
  Approximately 3.5 linear feet (7 boxes), arranged alphabetically by last name. Representing the largest series in the collection, these files were maintained for individuals who presented papers, served as co-chairs or were discussants. The files include correspondence, personal greeting cards, abstracts, curriculum vitae, newsletters, journals and clippings. Items of note include Vera D. Rubin's opening remarks (see Box 12, Folder 130) and articles, book reviews and earlier writings by and about conference presenters. For the original manuscript papers delivered at the 1984 conference, see Series XI. Conference Manuscripts. Duplicate copies of the manuscripts, taken from the Library of Caribbean Research, are listed in the Appendix. A select number of these papers were also part of a planned publication (see Series XII. Yale Press Manuscripts and subsequently published (see Series XIII. Published Manuscripts).
  - Rene Acheen correspondence, Oct 1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - George Alleyne correspondence, curriculum vitae, Oct - Nov 1983; May 1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Sheldon Annis correspondence, clipping, Jan - Oct 1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - William Aho correspondence, curriculum vitae, Item: posters for steel pan music, Jun 1984; Jan 1985; undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Frank McGlynn, Marcelo Alfonso correspondence, Mar - Aug 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Michael V. Angrosino correspondence, clipping, Oct - Nov 19893; Apr - Jun 1984; Jan 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Diane J. Austin correspondence, abstract, book review, Caribbean studies brochure, Oct - Dec 1983; Feb - July 1984; Feb 1985; undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Jaime Balcazar correspondence, ephemera, Feb - July 1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Linda Basch correspondence, abstract, ephemera, Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - George L. Beckford correspondence, Jan - Oct 1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Richard Bernal correspondence, Oct - Nov 1983; Feb - Jun 1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Lloyd Best correspondence, Mss., abstracts, ephemera, Jan - Dec 1984 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Lloyd Best correspondence, article, Jun - July 1985; undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Demetrio Boersner correspondence, article, ephemera, Apr - Aug 1984; Feb 1985; undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - O. Nigel Bolland correspondence, Oct - Nov 1983; Feb - Oct. 1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Samuel Bosch correspondence, Oct - Dec 1983 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Frank Bonilla, Ricardo Campos correspondence, Mss., abstract, published articles, ephemera, Dec 1982; Oct 1983; Feb - Jul 1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Thomas Bossert correspondence, abstract, article, ephemera, Jun 1984; undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Philippe Bourgois correspondence, abstracts, Apr - Nov 1984; Aug 1985; May 1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Kamau Brathwaite correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - Aug 1984 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Lloyd Braithwaite correspondence, Apr - July 1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Roy Bryce-Laporte correspondence, notes, Oct 1983; Feb - Jul 1984; undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Haywood Burns correspondence, notes, Aug 1984; undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Judy Butler correspondence, slide script: The Atlantic Coast, Aug - Sept 1984 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Jan Carew correspondence, Apr 1984 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Michael Carmack correspondence, abstract, ephemera, Oct; [1983]; Jan 1984 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Peter Carr correspondence, abstracts, notes, Oct - Dec 1983; Feb - July 1984; undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wilfred Cartey correspondence, notes, biographical article, Jun - Nov 1983; Feb - July 1984 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Jean Casimir correspondence, abstract, greeting card, ephemera, Apr - Jul 1984; undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Suzy Castor, Gerard Pierre-Charles, correspondence, ephemera, Item: correspondence regarding visa, Oct - Nov 1983; Jan - Apr. 1984 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Suzy Castor, Gerard Pierre-Charles, correspondence, curriculum vitae, visa forms, ephemera, May - Sept 1984; undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Anne Chapman correspondence, abstract, Oct - Dec 1983; Feb - July 1984 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Robin Cohen correspondence, review article, Oct - Nov 1983; Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Johnetta B. Cole correspondence, Oct 1983; Jul 1984 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Joseph Cook correspondence, Oct - Dec 1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Susan Craig correspondence, notes, Oct - Dec 1983; Jan - Aug 1984 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Michael Craton correspondence, ephemera, abstracts, Oct - Nov 1983; Feb - Oct 1984 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Theo R. Crevenna correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - Feb 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Peter Dalton correspondence, abstract, Oct - Nov 1983; Jan - Sept 1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Rita Giacalone de Romero correspondence, abstract, Jan - July 1984; undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Guarocuya Batista del Villar correspondence, abstract, articles, ephemera, May - Oct 1983; Jan - Aug 1984; undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - William Demas correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - Feb 1984 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Ramesh Deosaran correspondence, ephemera, May - July 1984 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - John M. Donahue, correspondence, clippings, book review, Oct - Nov 1983; Feb - Jun 1984; undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Melanie Dreher correspondence, abstract, Oct - Nov 1983; Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - W. W. Dressler correspondence, abstracts, articles, Oct - Nov 1983; Feb - July 1984 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Israel D. Drori, Peretz Ram correspondence, Mar - Nov 1983; Jan - Jun 1984; undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Neville Duncan correspondence, curriculum vitae, Oct 1983; Jan - Jul 1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Luis Echeverria [Alvarez] correspondence, newsletter, Feb 1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Locksley Edmondson correspondence, profile, Mss, Oct - Nov 1983; May - Aug 1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Michael Erisman correspondence, abstract, Oct - Dec 1983; Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Kenneth Paul Erikson correspondence, Oct 1983; Jul 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Trevor M. A. Farrell correspondence, abstracts, Oct 1983; Jan - Aug 1984; Mar 1985; undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Richard E. Feinberg correspondence, book review, Oct - Dec 1983; Feb - Oct 1984; undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Manuel Moreno Fraginals, correspondence, abstract, curriculum vitae, clipping, greeting card on the 25th anniversary of the Cuban Revolution, Oct 1983; Jan - July 1984; Dec 1985; undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Monica Frolander-Ulf correspondence, Oct 1983; Feb - Mar 1984 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Carlos Fuentes correspondence, Oct - Nov 1983; Oct 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Richard Garfield correspondence, abstract, articles, ephemera, Dec 1983; Sep 1982; Feb - Oct 1984; undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Eugenia Georges correspondence, ephemera, Oct 1983; Jan - Apr 1984 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Margaret Gilpin, A.C.S.W. correspondence, funding proposal, article, curriculum vitae, ephemera, Jun - Sept 1983; Feb - Dec 1984; undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Norman P. Girvan correspondence, greeting card, ephemera, Oct 1983; Mar - July 1984; Jan 1985; undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Patrick I. Gomes correspondence, abstracts, ephemera, Oct 1983; Jan - Aug 1984 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Nancie L. Gonzalez correspondence, article, Jul - Nov 1983; Jan - Mar 1984 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - June Goodfield correspondence, Oct - Nov 1983; May 1984 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Trevor Gordon-Somers correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - Mar 1984 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Xavier Gorostiaga correspondence, ephemera, Nov 1983; Feb - Jul 1984; undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Eddie Greene correspondence, Oct - Nov 1983; May - Sept 1984 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Edmundo Gordon, Galio Gurdián, correspondence, clippings, report, ephemera, Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Kenneth O. Hall Correspondence, Aug 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Stuart Hall correspondence, Oct 1983; Feb - Apr 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ansley Hamid correspondence, abstracts, draft Mss., Oct 1983; Feb 1984; undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Jack Harewood correspondence, abstract, Mss., ephemera, Jul - Nov 1983; Jan - Jul 1984; undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Ivan Head correspondence, Oct - Nov 1983 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Jorge Heine correspondence, clippings, ephemera, Oct 1983; Jan - Aug 1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Alistair Hennessey Caribbean studies brochures, correspondence, abstract, ephemera, Jan - July 1984; undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Paget Henry correspondence, Oct - Nov 1983; July - Aug 1984 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Errol Hill correspondence, curriculum vitae, July - Oct 1983; May 1984 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Merle Hodge correspondence, greeting card, abstract, ephemera, Oct - Dec 1983; Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - James Hymes correspondence, Oct 1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - A. J. Jaffe correspondence, World Fertility Survey (WFS) publication lists, abstract, Nov 1982; Sep 1983; Feb - Oct 1984; undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Michel S. Laguerre correspondence, ephemera, Mar - Aug 1984; undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - George Lamming correspondence, clippings, ephemera, Oct 1983; Jan - Aug 1984; undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Paul R. Latortue correspondence, abstract, May - July 1984 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Tilden LeMelle correspondence, Sept - Oct 1983; Apr - July 1984 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Leslie Lett correspondence, Aug - Sept 1984; Feb - Jun 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Vaughn Lewis correspondence, abstract, Jan - Oct 1984 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Shirley Lindenbaum correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - July 1984 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Louis Lindsey correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan 1984 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Neville Linton correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - July 1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Verne W. Loose correspondence, proposal, ephemera; Item: original conference Mss. has hand painted cover, Aug - Nov 1983; Feb - July 1984 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Earl Lovelace correspondence, Oct 1983; Jun - July 1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Theodore MacDonald correspondence, ephemera, Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Michael Maggio correspondence, abstract, clipping, Apr - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Lucille Mair correspondence, clipping, Oct - Nov 1983; Apr - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Jay R. Mandle correspondence, abstract, Oct - Dec 1983; Feb - July 1984 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Leslie F. Manigat correspondence, newsletter, clipping, political brochure, Sept - Oct 1983; Jan - Jun 1984; undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Michael Manley correspondence, clippings, Item: article re Edna Manley, Oct 1983; Mar - Aug 1984; undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Robert A. Manners correspondence, Oct 1983; July - Sept 1984 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Frank E. Manning correspondence, abstracts, clippings, Oct 1983; Feb - May 1984; Jan 1985; undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Francis Marks correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan 1984 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Perry Mars correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - Jun 1984 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Marco Mason correspondence, ephemera, Jan - Oct 1984 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Raymond Masse correspondence, Oct 1983 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Jocelyn Massiah correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan 1984 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - David Maybury-Lewis correspondence, Oct 1983 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Val McComie correspondence, clipping, ephemera, Oct 1983; Jan - July 1984 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Alister McIntyre correspondence, ephemera, Oct - Nov 1983; Apr - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Frank McGlynn correspondence, Univ. of Pittsburgh brochure, Sept - Oct 1983; Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Carmelo Meso-Lago correspondence, Oct 1983 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Don Mills correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - July 1984 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Sidney Mintz correspondence, Oct - Nov 1983; May - Sept 1984 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Jose Moreno correspondence, Oct - Dec 1983; Feb - May 1984 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Joseph Murphy correspondence, form letters clippings, CUNY administrators list, ephemera, Nov 1983; Jan - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Gerald F. Murray correspondence, abstracts, May - Sept 1984 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - June Nash correspondence, Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Roy Neehall correspondence, Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Rex Nettleford correspondence, Oct - Nov 1983; Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - David Nicholls correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - Mar 1984 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Abioseh Davidson Nicol correspondence, clipping, Feb - May 1984 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Maurice A. Odle correspondence, abstract, Oct 1983; Jan - Jun 1984; undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Carl D. Parris correspondence, abstract, Jan - Aug 1984; undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Peter D. Phillips correspondence, abstract, Jan - Aug 1984; undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Ken Post correspondence, abstract, article, Jun - Dec 1983; Feb - Aug 1984 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Angel G. Quintero-Rivera correspondence, postcard, abstracts, Oct - Dec 1983; Jan - Aug 1984; Jan -85 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Roderick Rainford correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - Sept 1984 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Kenneth Ramchand correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - July 1984 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Gordon Rohlehr correspondence, Oct 1983; Jan - July 1984 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Margurite Ross-Barnett correspondence, greeting card, clippings, ephemera, Oct - Nov 1983; Jan - Aug 1984 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - James Rowe correspondence, Interciencia journal, Jan - Aug 1984 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Vera D. Rubin clippings, printed matter: The Nation, "Casa de las Americas," Patricia Higgins, Human Organization, Mar - Aug 1984 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Helen Safa correspondence, abstract, ephemera, Oct - Nov 1983; May - Aug 1984; undated (Box 12, Folder 6)